<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Ruminations</title><link href="http://localhost:8000/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="http://localhost:8000/feeds/pages.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>http://localhost:8000/</id><updated>2013-05-03T18:23:00+05:30</updated><entry><title>About Me</title><link href="http://localhost:8000/about.html" rel="alternate"></link><updated>2013-05-03T18:23:00+05:30</updated><author><name>Sandeep Nangia</name></author><id>tag:localhost:8000,2013-05-03:about.html</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Picture of Sandeep Nangia" src="/pics/sn.jpg" title="Sandeep Nangia" /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a Master of Technology degree in Computer Science &amp;amp; Engineering from IIT Kanpur and a Bachelor’s of Engineering again in Computer Science &amp;amp; Engineering from Punjab Engineering College (now renamed to PEC University of Technology, a deemed university). Currently, I am an independent IT consultant. I have about 20+ years of experience in the IT sector. You can read more about my professional profile on &lt;a href="http://in.linkedin.com/in/sandeepnangia"&gt;LinkedIn&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I intend to blog here on the things that interest me like:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Indian Culture: specifically &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sanskrit"&gt;Saṃskṛta&lt;/a&gt; and various &lt;a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Stotra"&gt;Stotras&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Programming problems solved just for fun (usually in &lt;a href="http://clojure.org/"&gt;Clojure&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href="http://www.python.org/"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt;).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technology&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I studied Saṃskṛta till class 12th and then, off and on, I have kept in touch with it. The topic of my Master’s dissertation was “Sandhi Analysis using Two-Level Morphology” where I tried to apply Finite State Transducers to the problem of Sandhi Analysis. I have been doing a little bit of service at &lt;a href="http://www.kathamrita.org"&gt;Sri Ma Trust&lt;/a&gt; and that has allowed me to keep in touch with Sanskrit over the years. And then, sometime back, I found friends who were avid Saṃskṛta enthusiasts and that has kindled a new interest in Saṃskṛta. Currently, I am studying Vedapāṭha and Aṣṭādhyāyī from two separate teachers. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Credits&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This site has been created with the &lt;a href="http://getpelican.com"&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href="http://www.python.org/"&gt;Python&lt;/a&gt; based 
static blog generator. The theme used is &lt;a href="https://github.com/nangia/pelican-octopress-theme"&gt;pelican-octopress-theme&lt;/a&gt; which has been adapted from &lt;a href="https://github.com/duilio/pelican-octopress-theme"&gt;duilio&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href="https://github.com/jakevdp/pelican-octopress-theme"&gt;jakevdp&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</summary></entry></feed>